### lesson 1
Exercise.create( question: "Let's write a simple query.  Find all the available information about all the <em>schools</em>.", response_correct: "Very good!  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/1/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/1/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn about databases and tables.  Write your first query!", result_set_hash: "2acdeb39312427c9e853c3f10356565a41fd91edddce6aacf9dd53b5807afb30", lesson_id: 1)

Exercise.create( question: "Let's write another simple query.  Find all the available information about all the <em>locales</em>.", response_correct: "Purrrrfect!  You're getting the hang of it now.  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/2\">next lesson</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/1/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn about databases and tables.  Write your first query!", result_set_hash: "74bb695a25eccdd5ebaf072b5a077a9c7eab69b4af86bfbd440ae33c02b06a03", lesson_id: 1)

### lesson 2
Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools where the city is <em>Athens</em>.", response_correct: "Superb!  You were exactly right!  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/2/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>.", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/2/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to limit your query results with <em>where clauses</em>.", result_set_hash: "3e7e08ff1bb8ce22af764bbef05affaa36ad45af2736639ac021ae266bd529cb", lesson_id: 2)

Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools where the zip is <em>75241</em>.", response_correct: "All right!  That was great!  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/3\">next lesson</a>.", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/2/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to limit your query results with <em>where clauses</em>.", result_set_hash: "1722ddfb13cf1d5a80bf92fd806484bc99eb28f628cb764eeb5f3de904d660ba", lesson_id: 2)

### lesson 3
Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools where the chief's name contains the text <em>stan</em>.", response_correct: "Well done!  That was exactly what I was looking for.  Try out the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/3/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>.", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/3/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to search for segments of text with the <em>like</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "e9c9f762a242b04220c9e57b959502ac5183ddc21475aacb5d290126b6cfb574", lesson_id: 3)

Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about websites where the url contains the text <em>pdf</em>.", response_correct: "Purrrrfect!  You can give the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/4\">next lesson</a> a try if you're ready!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/3/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to search for segments of text with the <em>like</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "c48c00dc473ec2fe15b3428989d43e60e33bf6e61778564df818a6b2521c3bb0", lesson_id: 3)

### lesson 4
Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools where the chief's name contains the text <em>laura</em> or the chief's name contains the text <em>carroll</em>.", response_correct: "Purrrrfect!  I'm so proud of you.  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/4/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/4/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to write queries with more than one <em>where clause</em> using an <em>or</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "38779e8aecc138a3ea62acdd5445a346dc155cb6fb5343ec5507ed15456f9498", lesson_id: 4)

Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about websites where the url contains the text <em>audio</em> or the url contains the text <em>video</em>.", response_correct: "Yes!  You are totally <em>paw</em>-some! Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/5\">next lesson</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/4/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to write queries with more than one <em>where clause</em> using an <em>or</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "7f3d9a679559a7bd65a7543b82f0252c827c9d8cd05f3638bd12ac481ec35406", lesson_id: 4)

### lesson 5
Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools where the chief's name contains the text <em>laura</em> and the chief's name <strong>also</strong> contains the text <em>carroll</em>.",  response_correct: "Correct!  You are awesome <strong>AND</strong> amazing! Move on to the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/5/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/5/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to write queries with more than one <em>where clause</em> using an <em>and</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "d3867a7693f9f1cc482c0a060b6e0501073a42a152a3c914d3709f52cc168d5b", lesson_id: 5)

Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about websites where the url contains the text <em>www2</em> and the classification exactly matches <em>general</em>.",  response_correct: "Woohoo!  Very well done!  Move on to the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/6\">next lesson</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/5/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to write queries with more than one <em>where clause</em> using an <em>and</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "7c4c1e46916c36a44ad0a3403b0ae279b6d5ce3c67149266116e0264a0dd80eb", lesson_id: 5)

### lesson 6
Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools from the city of <em>Houston</em> that are not in the state <em>TX</em>.", response_correct: "Excellent!  You're learning so much!  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/6/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/6/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to filter results by inequality using the <em>does not equal</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "61e62c5c19ad48eeb3546acdbfb384f4e24bb8cd9837f9e427aefb1bbc2cf2aa", lesson_id: 6)

Exercise.create( question: "Find all available information about schools where the name contains the text <em>Washington</em> that are not in the state <em>WA</em>.", response_correct: "Yeah!  Keep it up!  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/7\">next lesson</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/6/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to filter results by inequality using the <em>does not equal</em> operator.", result_set_hash: "914eb24dea894f4c6a70f17585e0d5bd26180d2dc67761bce48394b15ea71fe0", lesson_id: 6)

### lesson 7
Exercise.create( question: "Find the name, city, and state of the schools in which the chief's name contains the text <em>victor</em>.", response_correct: "Beautiful!  I knew you could do it.  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/7/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/7/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Learn how to return specific columns from the table you are querying.", result_set_hash: "27936c07191e0f0a2cf21561ccb23da9431f668260b9a7d64ab18bccd3e2b925", lesson_id: 7)

Exercise.create( question: "Find the name, city, and state of schools from the state of <em>NY</em> in which the name of the school contains the text <em>medical</em>.", response_correct: "Purrrrfect!  You're doing so well!  Only <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/8\">the next lesson</a> is left.", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/7/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Get extra practice returning only specific columns from the table you are querying.", result_set_hash: "a9593831ef50fb6bb15fabb8bb0da0d04f6e6939c3ae445b5951b473abaf3600", lesson_id: 7)


### lesson 8
Exercise.create( question: "Find the school name and the name of its locale for all schools whose name contains the text <em>Penn State</em> .", response_correct: "Exactly right!  There's not much left to go!  Try the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/8/exercises/2\">next exercise</a>!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/8/exercises/1/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Write a complex query that pulls data from multiple tables.  Learn how to avoid <em>cartesian products</em>.", result_set_hash: "3f5ff9f3913199feb59601aba8a8833a90df3aa16d5b85e824c4b280df574888", lesson_id: 8)

Exercise.create( question: "Find the school name and the url and classification of its websites for any schools where the city matches <em>University Park</em> .", response_correct: "Wonderful!  You're almost done!  There's only the <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/8/exercises/3\">next exercise</a> left!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/8/exercises/2/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Write another complex query that pulls data from multiple tables.", result_set_hash: "874a0438aa6f83d3369fd789a260a427cd501e4590222873efc7b9cef9836ac9", lesson_id: 8)

Exercise.create( question: "Find the school name and city and the website url of all schools in the state of 'PA' whose website url contains the text <em>CommonApp</em> .", response_correct: "I knew you could do it!  You're all done!", response_incorrect: "Hmm.  The query you wrote ran successfully, but it didn't find the information I was looking for.  Would you like to <a class=\"message-anchor\" href=\"/lessons/8/exercises/3/edit\">try again</a>?", description: "Write a complex query that pulls data from multiple tables.  Learn how to avoid <em>cartesian products</em>.", result_set_hash: "56e148aa3f8e520e209d4b024eefb59f25830fd75c640c809e79999b0dad0dd6", lesson_id: 8)



######
# add dummy_id field now
exercises = Exercise.all
current_lesson = 1
current_exercise = 1

exercises.each do |exercise|
	if exercise.lesson_id != current_lesson
		current_lesson += 1
		current_exercise = 1
	end

	exercise.update(dummy_id: current_exercise)
	current_exercise += 1
end